[{"id": "6010c7130775fa611bce67d5", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"Sic semper tyrannis\" mean?", "answer": "\"Thus always to tyrants\" -- It is short for \"Sic semper tyrannis ad mortem\", which means \"Thus always I bring death to tyrants\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b8", "question": "Who played the alien high commander in the TV show \"3rd Rock from the Sun\"?", "answer": "John Lithgow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c7", "question": "A silk-screened print is also known as what?", "answer": "Serigraph", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339085", "question": "What is considered as the first daily comic strip in the US?", "answer": "Mutt and Jeff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc1b36ce05a3942286f13", "question": "In the \"Captain America: The Winter Soldier\" film, who was Winter Soldier?", "answer": "Bucky Barnes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5922028ca4edfd43a087addf", "question": "How many strings are there on the \"Spanish Guitar\"?", "answer": "Six", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecc", "question": "What rapper performs at the \"Mitch-a-palooza\" in the movie \"Old School\"?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30f", "question": "Who sang the 1979 song \"Family Tradition\"?", "answer": "Hank Williams Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cd40b9e685cf15b733e988a", "question": "In which county in the United Kingdom is the Glastonbury Festival held?", "answer": "Somerset", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a28", "question": "What car model gave its name to an alien in \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "Ford Prefect", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339897", "question": "What classic movie starred Vivien Leigh and Scarlett O'Hara?", "answer": "Gone With the Wind", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b4", "question": "In The Simpsons, who sings to Homer and the other astronauts in space?", "answer": "James Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b638", "question": "When an entree is prepared \"en brochette\", how is it served?", "answer": "On a skewer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23e", "question": "What royal subject married Wallis Simpson?", "answer": "Edward VIII", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bb356ef2627b8fe95581be0", "question": "Other than English, what is the main language in Guam?", "answer": "Chamorro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b5718d467df192a942e3362", "question": "Who popularized the game of Bingo in the United States?", "answer": "Edwin Lowe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1ca3b5a031299b745734", "question": "What is used to flavour Kriek lambic?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592204f8a4edfd43a087ade7", "question": "Who was the top scorer at the 2014 FIFA World Cup?", "answer": "James Rodriguez", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c101", "question": "What is the official language of Austria?", "answer": "German", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601737ef44491cbd7c5a1790", "question": "During World War II, prisoners wearing a green triangle in a concentration camp signified the prisoners were what?", "answer": "Criminals or convicts (often working as kapos)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3d", "question": "The novel \"War & Peace\" takes place during what Era?", "answer": "Napoleonic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7342beec85e375820b22f", "question": "Which U.S. aircraft carrier was lost during the Battle of the Coral Sea?", "answer": "The USS Lexington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5c106ce05a3942286e1d", "question": "Which Disney film features the song \"When You Wish Upon a Star\"?", "answer": "Pinocchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a899b4160d398dc9cf7a69b", "question": "Egg Fu is the enemy of what superhero?", "answer": "Wonder Woman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bc", "question": "U2's David Evans is better known by which nickname?", "answer": "The Edge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d35", "question": "What English town was William Shakespeare born in?", "answer": "Stratford-upon-Avon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a1a38012f2a7826b9b8727", "question": "Barbara Gordon is better know as what heroine?", "answer": "Batgirl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51342ff04d658268c92d7", "question": "What was the goal of the Marshall Plan?", "answer": "Rebuild war-devastated regions, remove trade barriers, modernize industry, and prevent the spread of communism.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b9", "question": "What do most lobsters and crayfish do with their shell after it has molted?", "answer": "Eat it", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4da", "question": "What fruit comes in Navel and Blood variety?", "answer": "Oranges", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a269", "question": "Turnov, Rusty and Bobo appear in what stage musical?", "answer": "Starlight Express", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e3", "question": "What is kept in a ship's binnacle?", "answer": "Compass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962e", "question": "What TV character sings the song \"Smelly Cat\"?", "answer": "Phoebe Buffay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa32", "question": "In which country is Cusco located?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0c", "question": "What is the primary ingredient in Soy Sauce, besides water?", "answer": "Wheat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39e", "question": "Who invented the cash register in 1879?", "answer": "James Ritty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339218", "question": "What is the theme song of the TV show \"Friends\" called?", "answer": "I'll Be There for You by The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b62a", "question": "What are known as \"buddy stores\"?", "answer": "Aircraft fuel tanks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de9", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"wok\"?", "answer": "Cantonese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca81", "question": "From what animal fat was margarine first made from in the US?", "answer": "Beef", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa4f06ce05a3942286eb9", "question": "What is Cat Stevens' birth name?", "answer": "Steven Demetrius Georgiou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c378", "question": "What tool did Charles Moncke invent?", "answer": "The monkey wrench", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a124", "question": "What do the prisoners call the escape tunnels in the film \"The Great Escape\"?", "answer": "Tom, Dick and Harry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8e", "question": "What Beatles song repeats the title in the lyrics forty-one times?", "answer": "Let It Be", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f031fe83fe1f2a824c10", "question": "The total number of years the Israelites spent in captivity is?", "answer": "430 -- The Israelite spent about 430 years in Egypt.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e54", "question": "What European city do Ethan Hawke and Julie Delpy wander in the movie \"Before Sunrise\"?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c467fbde8045e484669b", "question": "What is the color of a giraffe's tongue?", "answer": "Bluish-black -- This dark color helps protect the tongue from the sun as giraffes spend as much as 12 hours per day eating.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ef", "question": "How many squares are there on a standard Scrabble board?", "answer": "225", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc4", "question": "What does \"Flotsam\" describe?", "answer": "Floating wreckage of a ship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3f9dc73aa70ea0b70b01", "question": "What does the Japanese term \"Sandai Wagyu\" translate as?", "answer": "Three Big Beefs (Sandai Wagyu are \"the three big beefs\" - Matsusaka, \u014cmi and the most-famous of all, Kobe.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0b", "question": "What former US president founded the University of Virginia?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae94f4574a5ce6b56b824d", "question": "Which African country is Lilongwe the capital of?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d7", "question": "Luzon and Mindanao are the two largest islands of what country?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d92", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Ossessione\" based on?", "answer": "The Postman Always Rings Twice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fc8562fabc30a8194e188b0", "question": "In the film \"The Right Stuff\", who played the role of Chuck Yeager?", "answer": "Sam Shepard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358a0b5db0d66a186cb550", "question": "Which ocean does the African country, Burundi, has access to?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32a", "question": "Which character did Nick Nolte play in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Jack Cates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338931", "question": "What is the highest musical note on a standard 88-key piano?", "answer": "C8", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca38", "question": "Which element is fourth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Beryllium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339434", "question": "Who co-wrote and directed the 1974 movie \"Young Frankenstein\"?", "answer": "Mel Brooks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa39a6ce05a3942286ea5", "question": "What was the name of the Today Show's chimpanzee mascot?", "answer": "J. Fred Muggs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398bc", "question": "What rapper was born Marshall Bruce Mathers III?", "answer": "Eminem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75e", "question": "What organ gave us the word \"hysterical\"?", "answer": "The uterus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339870", "question": "In Disney's \"Peter Pan\", what other ingredient is needed for flight besides fairy dust?", "answer": "Thinking happy thoughts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b40201dd7bf43be5e7b9", "question": "What library has the most books in the U.S.?", "answer": "The Library of Congress", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e0", "question": "Which British sax player fronted the band \"Paraphernalia\"?", "answer": "Barbara Thompson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc0246de0eb824d4052d7", "question": "What city is known as the \"polar bear capital of the world\"?", "answer": "Churchill, Manitoba -- It's fairly common to see one strolling through the Canadian town or outside one's bedroom window at night.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fedd9936ce05a3942286d79", "question": "What was Red good at doing in prison in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Smuggling contraband into the prison.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339770", "question": "What movie features the four high school friends Jim, Finch, Oz and Kevin?", "answer": "American Pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d89", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Shawn Carter?", "answer": "Jay-Z", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ccf7a52b37b32637bdc44c0", "question": "What is the first foreign country you will reach if you go south from Miami, Florida.", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f482fa5fdd6dd25324e1", "question": "What show popularized the Humphrey Bogart line \"Yeah! That's the ticket\"?", "answer": "Saturday Night Live", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f53", "question": "Who is Dinah, whom Alice thinks about nostalgically as she falls down the rabbit hole to Wonderland?", "answer": "Her cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960d", "question": "What movie gave us the tagline \"The first casualty of war is innocence\"?", "answer": "Platoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb6", "question": "Who was the first African American to play in an NBA game?", "answer": "Earl Lloyd", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65797ae7e414034b5aede", "question": "Facebook co-founder Sean Parker was also the co-founder of which company?", "answer": "Napster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a5", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b5", "question": "How many pounds are there in a standard US ton?", "answer": "2,000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feccf31ec223966ae8f88b3", "question": "What is the name of Holly's cat in \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\"?", "answer": "Cat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60172ea944491cbd7c5a1780", "question": "During World War II, who was given the nickname \"Desert Fox\"?", "answer": "Johannes Erwin Eugen Rommel -- He was a German general and military theorist who served as field marshal in the Wehrmacht (armed forces) of Nazi Germany.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77d03224f0f7a362efd551", "question": "Who released an album called \"Don't Shoot Me I'm Only the Piano Player\" in 1973?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a80", "question": "Who wrote the novel Oryx and Crake?", "answer": "Margaret Atwood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbc", "question": "Which country was split into zones by the 'Yalta Agreement'?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87c", "question": "What chemical element has an extra syllable in its more correct British pronunciation?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ea", "question": "What type of snake is a Sidewinder?", "answer": "Rattlesnake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6c", "question": "The Camp David Accord negotiated peace between which two countries?", "answer": "Egypt and Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f0", "question": "Who painted \"The Boy in the Red Vest\"?", "answer": "Paul C\u00e9zanne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Apu's last name?", "answer": "Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d25", "question": "What was Winnie the Pooh's original name?", "answer": "Winnipeg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a419", "question": "What Scottish landmark borders on Fort Augustus?", "answer": "Loch Ness", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399de", "question": "Who was the only one of the six main characters on \"Friends\" to not get married at any time on the show?", "answer": "Joey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8c56ec223966ae8f8848", "question": "The 1994 \"Leon\" was the motion-picture debut of which one of its stars?", "answer": "Natalie Portman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e3", "question": "What fruit comes in Chubby Gray and Jubilee variety?", "answer": "Watermelons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3e", "question": "What pitcher with four World Series rings its nicknamed \"El Duque\"?", "answer": "Orlando Hernandez", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd49", "question": "Who appears on the cover of the \"Pokemon Yellow\" video game?", "answer": "Pikachu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b76", "question": "Whose novels include \"The Chamber\", \"The Client\", and \"The Firm\"?", "answer": "John Grisham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b536", "question": "What does an archer carry his arrows in?", "answer": "A Quiver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a481", "question": "Which two small states are surrounded by Italy?", "answer": "San Marino and the Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70b", "question": "Who brings gifts to the children of Brazil and Peru?", "answer": "Papa Noel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40d", "question": "What country is East Pakistan now known as?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f164acef9b80650dbe7f92c", "question": "How many British Admiral-class battlecruisers were cancelled in 1919?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ddd9fe83fe1f2a824b65", "question": "Which Crayola color was named by a five-year-old?", "answer": "Razzmatazz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f4", "question": "What was the first TV soap opera to regularly broadcast hour-long shows?", "answer": "Another World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899c2360d398dc9cf7a6a4", "question": "Who is the Roman goddess of the hearth, home and family?", "answer": "Vesta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a10", "question": "What year was the setting for the movie \"Animal House\"?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d1a72596a59cbdfbd385", "question": "In the film \"National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation,\" what did Aunt Bethany recite when ask to say a blessing?", "answer": "The American Pledge of Allegiance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c98f877e98cb977789f6", "question": "In which city was the oldest university in Scandinavia founded in 1477?", "answer": "Uppsala", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b78d", "question": "Cha dao is the art of what?", "answer": "Making tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b6f", "question": "Who wrote the novel series \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c4", "question": "Who played the role of Jenna Maroney on the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "Jane Krakowski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a093", "question": "What 1970's film came from a Pink Floyd tune?", "answer": "The Wall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acac", "question": "What kind of gun was used to kill Abraham Lincoln?", "answer": "A Derringer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe735abeec85e375820b24f", "question": "Who said, \"If you have ten thousand regulations you destroy all respect for the law.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23c", "question": "What royal subject married Marie Antoinette?", "answer": "Louis XVI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a3dfcf93664eb10486c0", "question": "Not including spin-offs or tie-ins, how many issues were released as part of the original \"Strangers in Paradise\" series that ended in 2007?", "answer": "90", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000ed109a72b906b34e3ce8", "question": "What hormone allows the cells in your body to absorb sugar from your blood?", "answer": "Insulin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c813fbde8045e48466ce", "question": "What digestive tract illness often is a manifestation of diabetes?", "answer": "Gastroparesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5921fce4a4edfd43a087adc4", "question": "What number is represented by \"X\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "10", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eac", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"Walk, Don't Run\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc44", "question": "What nationality is tennis player Novak Djokovic?", "answer": "Serbian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a1e512f2a7826b9b8716", "question": "What was the name given to the French goverment which collaborated with the Nazis?", "answer": "Vichy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff5129aff04d658268c92d1", "question": "What was the name of Woodrow Wilson's plan for peace after World War I?", "answer": "The Fourteen Points was a statement of principles for peace that was to be used for negotiations in order to end World War I.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdd5eca0499cffc60b84235", "question": "What did a shepherd boy discover at Qumran, Jordan, in 1946 and 1947?", "answer": "Dead Sea Scrolls", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff7c28f2b316f4693fb67a1", "question": "Which candy company is known as the primary producer of \"conversation hearts\" in the United States?", "answer": "The New England Confectionary Company or NECCO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc0e46ce05a3942286f0a", "question": "What is the name of the British ship in the film \"Master and Commander: Far Side of the World\"?", "answer": "H.M.S. Surprise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdd5de60499cffc60b84232", "question": "Which country is ruled by the Al Sabah dynasty?", "answer": "Kuwait", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b5", "question": "How many strings does the common Bass guitar have?", "answer": "4", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a803", "question": "What city is overlooked by a large statue named \"Christ the Redeemer\"?", "answer": "Rio de Janeiro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd2", "question": "What US city was destroyed by an earthquake in 1906?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b479e662d71a53650feb", "question": "Why did Michelangelo dislike Raphael?", "answer": "He thought Raphael was copying him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ba", "question": "Which river is often viewed as Russia's national river?", "answer": "Volga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9ba81364247bf200fb898", "question": "Which political party was co-founded in West Germany in 1979 by the late Petra Kelly?", "answer": "The Green Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fb", "question": "What sport features strikers and sweepers?", "answer": "Soccer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb1be8df497e33de8057918", "question": "Who scored the first counted three-point basket in NBA history?", "answer": "Chris Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338927", "question": "What two letters in American Sign Language require a finger movement?", "answer": "J and Z", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597ddb6777980686f722d176", "question": "What year was the first patent for a pencil sharpener applied for?", "answer": "1828", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69d1020565ad31a57c774", "question": "Which U.S. president officially gave the White House its name?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339552", "question": "What TV show centered on the exploits of physicist Dr. Sam Beckett?", "answer": "Quantum Leap", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b292", "question": "What piece of technology did IBM develop in 1973 that they nicknamed Winchester?", "answer": "A disk drive", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a728c666bcd28c119383286", "question": "What year was the first edition of \"The Guinness Book of Records\" published?", "answer": "1955", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133953f", "question": "How were the parents of the siblings on the TV show \"Party of Five\" killed?", "answer": "Car accident", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fb", "question": "What Olympic event is abbreviated to WAG?", "answer": "Women's Artistic Gymnastics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b32333cbf195a31e15d7399", "question": "Gaborone is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395aa", "question": "Who played Elliot Ness in the 1987 movie \"The Untouchables\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ebf", "question": "Whose girlfriends are named Callie Shaw and Iola Morton?", "answer": "The Hardy Boys", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76a", "question": "How many colors were there in the first boxes of Crayola crayons sold in 1903?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a497", "question": "Which desert is found in South East Mongolia and Northern China?", "answer": "Gobi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9acaebfabb9c85d8a97f", "question": "Stilton cheese originates from which country?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67a", "question": "What animal builds dams across streams?", "answer": "The beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecf", "question": "What animated film begins in Shiverpool, Antarctica?", "answer": "Surf's Up", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c787", "question": "What car manufacturer was first to introduce seat belts as a standard feature?", "answer": "Saab", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339658", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", why did Bart and Homer have to work at the carnival?", "answer": "Bart wrecked Hitler's car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d117014fea7fe947a22276", "question": "Mickey Mouse is known as what in Italy?", "answer": "Topolino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c548", "question": "How wide is the average bolt of lightning?", "answer": "1/2 inch", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf8e", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 608?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4a", "question": "What drink, created in 1886, was first advertised as \"delicious and refreshing\"?", "answer": "Coca Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51247ff04d658268c92ce", "question": "Cleopatra represented herself as the reincarnation of what Egyptian goddess?", "answer": "Cleopatra represented herself as the reincarnation of the Egyptian goddess\u00a0Isis.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a94e661d1b4d384d5d673", "question": "Elzie Segar created what popular character?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b181", "question": "During World War II, Spain fought for which side - Axis or Allies?", "answer": "Neither, Spain was neutral", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f165ff048f679a45aab1", "question": "How do crocodiles keep cool?", "answer": "They release heat through their mouths", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c82", "question": "What year did Sting release his first solo album after leaving The Police?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be57f6c5415ba52ed6f0aaa", "question": "What type of creature is a \"sidewinder\"?", "answer": "A snake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b237", "question": "May Day, as an international workers' celebration, dates back to what 1886 event?", "answer": "The Haymarket labor riot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae67", "question": "What nationality was Christopher Columbus?", "answer": "Italian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab08", "question": "Apia is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Samoa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008ca4cf842fa4c4ba96a0", "question": "What is Jimmy Carter's middle name?", "answer": "Earl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133997f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Krusty the Clown's helper monkey?", "answer": "Mr. Teeny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ec2a08d98002fdd633b8", "question": "Which singer's autobiography is titled \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7ca3f877e98cb97778a04", "question": "What Cape will you find at the tip of Africa?", "answer": "Cape of Good Hope", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d5", "question": "In 1991, who finally broke Bob Beamon's decades-old long jump record?", "answer": "Mike Powell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338deb", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"cookie\"?", "answer": "Dutch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aedd", "question": "Who was president of the US from 1953 to 1961?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99e", "question": "What well known drug comes from the cinchona tree?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa63", "question": "Mauritania is in which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a62", "question": "What 1984 comedy is credited with the popularity of the girl's name, Madison?", "answer": "Splash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017402944491cbd7c5a17bb", "question": "Who ruled Soviet Russia from 1917 to 1922?", "answer": "Vladimir Lenin -- this was the period between the Russian Revolution and the formation of the Soviet Union (U.S.S.R.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339510", "question": "Who played Molly's love interest in the movie \"Pretty in Pink\"?", "answer": "Andrew McCarthy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a9b520565ad31a57c809", "question": "Who was President George Washington's Secretary of War?", "answer": "Henry Knox", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac7", "question": "Which superhero\u2019s powers could be taken away by the color yellow?", "answer": "Green Lantern", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a728cbe6bcd28c11938328b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Delaware?", "answer": "Dover", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c728", "question": "Who was the first man to return safely from space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339471", "question": "Who plays the role of Franz Liebkind in the 2005 movie \"The Producers\"?", "answer": "Will Ferrel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c15", "question": "Who are the four main characters of the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Stan, Kyle, Cartman and Kenny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e8", "question": "The \"Robots in Disguise\" are better known as what?", "answer": "Transformers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fa", "question": "Who played the role of Grant in the 1966 film \"Fantastic Voyage\"?", "answer": "Stephen Boyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdffc3e1cf6db9ac4808cfc", "question": "What part of Russia is surrounded by Lithuania and Poland?", "answer": "Kaliningrad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa57", "question": "Which country has Budapest as its capital?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b0", "question": "What do the Scoville Heat Units indicate?", "answer": "The amount of capsaicin present", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c432", "question": "How many pairs of ribs are there in the average human skeleton?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a242", "question": "At the end of the TV series \"M*A*S*H\", what character stayed in Korea?", "answer": "Maxwell Q. Klinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d9aff08b8581f80b092c1", "question": "What cartoon character did artist Matt Furie decide to kill in 2017, after it became associated with white nationalism against his will?", "answer": "Pepe the Frog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339182", "question": "Who was the actor who played Charles in the movie \"Four Weddings and a Funeral\"?", "answer": "Hugh Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338899", "question": "Who were the Three Musketeers?", "answer": "Arthos, Porthos, Aramis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03c", "question": "What was the name of the sect that was raided by the FBI in Waco, Texas in 1993?", "answer": "Branch Davidians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a1e1ceab5a031299b745736", "question": "Who saved Andromeda from the sea monster?", "answer": "Perseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba42", "question": "What is the eagle in the Great Seal of the United States holding in its right talon?", "answer": "Olive branch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae85e134007905755f79e86", "question": "In chronological order, what is the first book in the Chronicles of Narnia series?", "answer": "The Magician\u2019s Nephew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339548", "question": "What kind of TV ads were banned in the US in 1970?", "answer": "Cigarette ads", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339598", "question": "Wesley Snipes and Woody Harrelson work as hustlers in what 1992 film?", "answer": "White Men Can't Jump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a47", "question": "What comic strip was set in the Okeefenokee Swamp?", "answer": "Pogo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9cf", "question": "On what number is the decimal system based?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5cf", "question": "What is the largest inland lake in South America?", "answer": "Titicaca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7704eeec85e375820b2f7", "question": "What republic claims to be the world's oldest surviving republic?", "answer": "San Marino", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e4", "question": "What was known as \"the gun that won the West\"?", "answer": "The Winchester Rifle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae90", "question": "Which US president resided at the Hermitage, a plantation in Tennessee?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b578", "question": "How many teaspoons are there in a cup?", "answer": "48", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b83", "question": "What is the name of the evolutionary biologist who wrote \"The God Delusion\"?", "answer": "Richard Dawkins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65c641f3c0ead6880d614", "question": "Before starting Wendy's, what fast food franchise did Dave Thomas work for?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339465", "question": "Who wrote the movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad44", "question": "What is the maiden name of former first lady Betty Ford?", "answer": "Bloomer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b9", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives was Anne Boleyn's cousin?", "answer": "Catherine Howard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a491", "question": "Which country do Belgium, France and Germany border?", "answer": "Luxembourg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0b", "question": "Hockey legend Wayne Gretzky was born in what year?", "answer": "1961", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339790", "question": "What is the name of the mansion where Elvis Presley died?", "answer": "Graceland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339920", "question": "Robert Duvall, Marlon Brando, and Harrison Ford all appeared in what movie?", "answer": "Apocalypse Now", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f9", "question": "What does IQ stand for?", "answer": "Intelligence Quotient", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59524530736d4be723796b6c", "question": "What French impressionist painter died in 1926", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d70a2596a59cbdfbd3b1", "question": "Who invented corn flakes?", "answer": "Dr. John Harvey Kellogg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f1", "question": "Shortbread originated in what country?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe93dc86bd93ce3a4e5f6b9", "question": "How long is one Pluto year?", "answer": "248 Earth years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdca", "question": "What off-road endurance race is named after the African capital where it usually ends?", "answer": "The Dakar Rally", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c3", "question": "Which videgame franchise had frequent segments on The Super Mario Bros. Super Show?", "answer": "The Legend of Zelda", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b927", "question": "What were ivories to an old west gambler?", "answer": "Dice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f31301dd7bf43be5e814", "question": "What does AFLAC stand for in the US?", "answer": "American Family Life Assurance Company of Columbus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d07671a1c922dd1ac64b8", "question": "The average adult human has 32 of what?", "answer": "Teeth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28d", "question": "What is the fruit of the \"Ananas comosus\"?", "answer": "A pineapple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925d", "question": "What 1981 movie required some 7,000 snakes?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72e", "question": "What country had, at one time, a female \"Santa\" called Babouschka?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b69930be762b54eb9be9428", "question": "In which US state would you find Twenty Lake?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339033", "question": "Who wrote the the novel \"The Dam Busters\"?", "answer": "Paul Brickhill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa3ce6ce05a3942286eaa", "question": "Which of the Beach Boys actually knew how to surf?", "answer": "Dennis Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79c", "question": "What is the name of Neptune's largest moon?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec0", "question": "\"The Da Vinci Code\" repeats the myth that the glass pyramid in front of the Louvre consists of how many panes?", "answer": "666", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4afd49076251badbeabf", "question": "What was the first food to be intentionally microwaved?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c658", "question": "Mach refers to the speed of what?", "answer": "Sound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede4396ce05a3942286dda", "question": "Which famous drummer was nicknamed \"The Beast\" while intoxicated?", "answer": "John Bonham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab90", "question": "What was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer Empire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c5", "question": "Who produced two booklets for \"Comic Relief\" under the names Newt Scamander and Kennilworthy Whisp?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec24ac8dc25ca9e12ef639", "question": "Who sang the track \"Think\" for the 1980 album \"The Blues Brothers: Original Soundtrack Recording\"?", "answer": "Aretha Franklin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b712", "question": "Which New York newspaper wrote \"yes Virginia, there is a Santa Claus\"?", "answer": "The New York Sun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c334", "question": "What percentage of air is composed of nitrogen?", "answer": "78%", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a2", "question": "What character did Christopher Lloyd play in the movie \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit?", "answer": "Judge Doom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389aa", "question": "What novel by Louisa May Alcott tells about the lives and loves of four sisters?", "answer": "Little Women", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a12c", "question": "Who sang the theme song to the Bond film \"The Spy Who Loved Me\"?", "answer": "Carly Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9bf", "question": "In which Mega Man game can you acquire the Gemini Laser?", "answer": "Mega Man 3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c6", "question": "Who played the role of Grizz on the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "Grizz Chapman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6e3ca9e54d890926f6c3", "question": "What is the oldest surviving structure in New York City?", "answer": "The Wyckoff Farmhouse -- Located in Brooklyn, it was built in 1652 and resembles many early Dutch-American farms of the time.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a774", "question": "What African country completely surrounds the country of Lesotho?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3dbbff048f679a45ab51", "question": "What enzyme is responsible for breaking down starches?", "answer": "Amylase", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597ddd3077980686f722d17c", "question": "When was the first permanent photograph taken?", "answer": "1826", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea497dff048f679a45abb9", "question": "Extending a joint beyond its normal anatomical position is called what?", "answer": "Hyperextension", "category": "science"}]